Guide to the Leo Bogart Papers, 1912-2010 and undated RL.10146
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Series, 1914-2005 and undated, 84 boxes
  - Writings and Speeches Subseries, 1943-2004 and undated
    - Speeches (Box 58)
      - 1966 Aug. 22, The Trend to Print in Advertising, Texas Daily Newspaper Association (Box 59)
      - 1966 Sept. 21, Social Sciences in the Mass Media, Columbia University Seminar on Basic and Applied Social Research (Box 59)
      - 1966 Nov. 22, Mouse Traps Revisited, AMA Detroit Chapter (Box 59)
      - 1967 Jan. 27, Advertisers! Can You Afford Not to Know?, INAE (Box 59)
      - 1967 Feb. 11, Pacific Chapter of the AAPOR panel discussion (Box 59)
      - 1967 Feb. 28, Mass Media in the Year 2000, Swedish ABC, 2 folders (Box 59)
      - 1967 May, No Opinion, Don't Know, and Maybe No Answer, AAPOR (Box 59)
      - 1967 June 21, Mass Media in the Year 2000, AMA (Box 59)
      - 1967 June 26, Seven Newspaper Points for Seven Minutes, American Advertising Federation (Box 59)
      - 1967 Oct. 19, The Changing Public: Its News Interests and Sources, APME (Box 59)
      - 1967 Nov. 26, The State of the Art, Arden House Seminar, Columbia University (Box 59)
      - 1968 Jan. 17, Newspaper Advertising: Moving Toward the Year 2000, INAE (Box 59)
      - 1968 May 24, Where Does Advertising Research Go From Here?, C.H. Sandage Symposium, University of Illinois (Box 59)
      - 1968 June 17, The Marketer as a Radical, AMA International Marketing Congress (Box 59)
      - 1968, NRMA convention speech notes (Box 59)
      - 1969 Mar. 12, Polls and Public Priorities, 25th anniversary of The Minneapolis Tribune's Minnesota Poll (Box 60)
      - 1969 May 17, Public Priorities, Power Politics, and Polls, AAPOR (Box 60)
      - 1970 Oct. 14, New England Weekly Publishers Association speech (Box 60)
      - 1970 Oct. 20, Television Rates, INCFO (Box 60)
      - 1971 June 9-12, National Conference for Professors of Advertising, University of Illinois speech (Box 60)
      - 1971 June 22, Association of Industrial Advertisers speech (Box 60)
      - 1971 Nov. 15, What Makes a Brand Visible?, ARF (Box 60)
      - 1971, Customers, Not 'Consumers,' ARF (Box 60)
      - 1972 Apr. 19, Columbia University seminar on social priorities speech (Box 60)
      - 1972 July 11, Public Relations Society of America speech (Box 60)
      - 1972 Sept. 6, Toward a Psychology of Sale, APA (Box 60)
      - 1972 Sept. 28, Advertising and marketing course lecture, Advertising Club of New York (Box 60)
      - 1972, speeches before Congress on social science research (Box 60)
      - 1973 Feb. 8, California Newspaper Publishers' Association speech (Box 60)
      - 1973 May 4, Choice for the Reader, Choice for the Press, ASNE (Box 60)
      - 1973 May 11, Whither Advertising?, AMA (Box 60)
      - 1973 May 27-29, The Management of Media: An Agenda for Research, Arden House Conference on Directions in Mass Communication Research (Box 60)
      - 1973 Oct. 3, University of Michigan Lectures in Journalism Series speech (Box 60)
      - 1973 Oct. 18, IAPA speech (Box 60)
      - 1974 Feb. 28, Isn't it Time to Reinvent Advertising Research?, ANA (Box 60)
      - 1974 July 2, The Circulation Coverage Picture, ICMA (Box 60)
      - 1974 Oct. 3, The Marketing of Public Goods, AMA (Box 60)
      - 1974 Nov. 18, Safety In Numbers?, ARF (Box 60)
      - 1974 Nov. 20, Will the Medium Get the Message?, APME (Box 60)
      - 1974, The Outlook For Newspapers (Box 60)
      - 1975 Mar. 11, Advertising Growth and Advertising Effectiveness, International Advertising Symposium (Box 60)
      - 1975 May 19, The Next Quarter Century of Newspaper Progress, INPA (Box 61)
      - 1975 Sept. 19, Is All This Advertising Really Necessary?, Market Research Council (Box 61)
      - 1975 Nov. 18, Supermarket Institute speech (Box 61)
      - 1975 Nov. 18, AAAA Eastern Region convention speech (Box 61)
      - 1975 Oct. 31, Is All This Advertising Really Necessary?, ACR (Box 61)
      - 1975 Dec., NRMA speech (Box 61)
      - 1976 Jan 13, Is All This Advertising Really Necessary?, IAA (Box 61)
      - 1976 May 5, The Readership Challenge, ANPA (Box 61)
      - 1976 July 28, Why Newspaper Circulation Will Go Up, ICMA (Box 61)
      - 1976 Aug. 30, The Automobile as Social Bond, ASA (Box 61)
      - 1976 Aug. 31, News as Reality and as Dream, ASA (Box 61)
      - 1976 Nov. 11, Chrysler meeting speech (Box 61)
      - 1977 May 1, Editorial Ideals, Editorial Illusions, ASNE (Box 61)
      - 1977 May 16, The View From the Bottom Line, INCFO (Box 61)
      - 1977 Sept. 22, Minorities as Readers of Newspapers, Conference on Minorities and the Media, Northwestern University (Box 61)
      - 1978 Feb. 2, Newspapers, Research, and the Marketing of Culture, Edward J. Meeman Lecture, University of Tennessee (Box 61)
      - 1978 Oct. 25, Readership Speech, The Library of Congress Center for the Book (Box 61)
      - 1981 Apr. 7, Scripps-Howard Business Managers' Conference (Box 61)
      - 1981 Nov. 5-8, Mass Media: Knowledge as Entertainment, Academy of Independent Scholars symposium (Box 61)
      - 1981, The Marketing Environment for Technological Change, ANPA (Box 61)
      - 1982 Mar. 2, A New Agenda for Advertising Research, ARF (Box 61)
      - 1982 May 11, Creative Marketing in U.S. Daily Newspapers, IFRA (Box 61)
      - 1982 June 21, Circulation: The Key to Successful Newspaper Marketing, ICMA (Box 62)
      - 1982 June 23, Will Newspapers Become a Class Medium?: Why They Need Not and Must Not, ANPA/RI (Box 62)
      - 1982 Aug 3, Telecommunications: The Competitive Technology, Teleinformatics seminar (Box 62)
      - 1982 Oct. 1, Lo Nuevo en el Medio Prensa y la Creatividad Publicitaria, Congreso Colombiano de Publicidad (Box 62)
      - 1982, Starting a New Newspaper (Box 62)
      - 1983 Jan. 11 How America Shops and Buys, NRMA (Box 62)
      - 1983 Aug. 8, How Do Your Papers Rate with Readers?, AEJMC (Box 62)
      - 1983 Sept. 14, Will They Come When Ye Do Call Them?, ARF (Box 62)
      - 1983 Nov. 4, How Newspaper Content is Changing, APME (Box 62)
      - 1983 Nov. 14, Newspapers, 1984, Seattle Ad Club (Box 62)
      - 1984 Mar. 20, The Medium that Fits Your Message, ASNE (Box 62)
      - 1985 Jan. 27-30, Selective Strategies for Success, INAME (Box 62)
      - 1985 July 30, Progress in Advertising Research?, ARF (Box 62)
      - 1986 Mar. 10-11, What Forces Shape the Future of Advertising Research, ANA (Box 62)
      - 1986 Aug. 25, The Many Meanings of Advertising, APA (Box 62)
      - 1986 Aug., The Big Change in Television presentation (Box 62)
      - 1987 Feb. 9, Research as an Instrument of Power, Gannett Center (Box 62)
      - 1987 June 8, The Competitive Challenge to Our Advertising, ANPA (Box 62)
      - 1987 Aug. 27, Die Suche, DIALOG conference (Box 62)
      - 1987, US-Zeitungen - Findet der Leser, was ihn Angeht? Warum?, DIALOG conference (Box 62)
      - 1987 Sept. 22-23, Las Turbulentas Profundidades del Marketing, Conferencias Internacional de Medios (Box 62)
      - 1988 Feb. 1, What Forces Shape the Future of Advertising Research?, ARF (Box 62)
      - 1988 Apr. 7, Advertising: Art, Science, or Business?, University of Illinois James Webb Young Address (Box 62)
      - 1988 May 18, Advertising: Art, Science, or Business?, MRDA (Box 62)
      - 1988 Nov. 11, Why Newspapers?, ANA (Box 62)
      - 1989 Mar. 16, Inserting in North America: Trends and Practices, IFRA (Box 62)
      - 1989 Apr. 12, A Look at Special Sections, ASNE (Box 62)
      - 1989 Apr. 25, Can Newspaper Competition be Revived?, ANPA (Box 62)
      - 1989 May 11, The State of Newspapers, Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars Media Studies Project (Box 62)
      - 1990 Feb. 19, Commercial Culture, Boulder, Colorado (Box 62)
      - 1990 Feb. 21, Fellows Seminar speech, New York (Box 63)
      - 1990 Apr. 5, The New Competitive Climate in Advertising, IFRA (Box 63)
      - 1990 June 12-13, The Threat for the Future of the Newspaper Market: Lessons For Europe From the U.S., Financial Times conference; London, England (Box 63)
      - 1990 Oct. 16, An Agenda for Newspaper Research, Newspaper Research Council (Box 63)
      - 1990 Nov. 5, The U.S. Newspaper Advertising Bureau: Its Lessons for Germany; Germany (Box 63)
      - 1991 May 6, Newspaper Advertising: Roller Coaster or Steady Slide?, ANPA; Vancouver, British Columbia (Box 63)
      - 1991 Sept. 5, Learning From the American Experience, Buenos Aires, Argentina (Box 63)
      - 1991 Nov. 7, The New Media and Advertising, Universidad de Navarra; Pamplona, Spain (Box 63)
      - 1994 Apr. 7, Advertising and the Information Superhighway, Bogotá, Colombia (Box 63)
      - 1994 Apr. 18-20, Advertising and the Information Superhighway, ARF (Box 63)
      - 1994 Apr. 23, Journalism and the Information Superhighway, San Francisco State University (Box 63)
      - 1994 Oct. 16, Advertising and the Telecommunications Revolution, ANA (Box 63)
      - 1995 Feb.22, On the Information Superhighway, Will Car Advertisers Be Taken For a Ride?, J.D. Power and Associates Automotive Advertising Strategy Conference (Box 63)
      - 1995 Oct. 31, Newspapers at the Millenium, International Newspaper Marketing Association; Lima, Peru (Box 63)
      - 1996 Apr. 12-13, The Changing Market for Journalism, Middle Tennessee State University journalism education conference (Box 63)
      - 1997 Feb. 6, The Latin American Press: Challenges and Achievements, World Meeting of Newspaper Organizations (Box 63)
      - 1998 Feb. 26-28, Journalism and Accountability, American Journalism Review (Box 63)
      - 1998 Apr. 15, Buying Services and the Media Marketplace, São Paulo, Brazil (Box 63)
      - 1999, Radio: 2000 and Beyond, Radio Free Europe Affiliate Assembly (Box 63)
      - 2000 Nov. 23, Weekend Editions: A Global Review, World Association of Newspapers; Berlin, Germany (Box 63)
      - 2003 Nov. 6, Media and Civility, Universidad de Navarra; Pamplona, Spain (Box 63)
      - 2004 Sept. 15, Innovations in Newspaper Marketing; Hyderabad, India (Box 63)
    - Writings (Box 64)
      - Articles
        - 1943 Sept., Soldier Thinking (Box 64)
        - 1949 Fall, Fan Mail for the Philharmonic (Box 64)
        - 1951 Mar., Use of Opinion Research (Box 64)
        - 1954 Jan., Outlook for UHF and Its 70 Channels (Box 64)
        - 1954 Aug., How to Use Magazine Readership Studies (Box 64)
        - 1954 Dec., The Army and Its Negro Soldiers (Box 64)
        - 1955 July, Adult Talk About Newspaper Comics (Box 64)
        - 1955 Oct., 8 Big Needs in Radio-TV Research (Box 64)
        - 1955 Dec., How Magazines are Withstanding TV (Box 64)
        - 1955, Radio: Listeners and Costs (Box 64)
        - 1955, Study of the Operating Assumptions of the U.S. Information Agency (Box 64)
        - 1956 Jan.-Feb., How to Get More Out of Marketing Research (Box 64)
        - 1956 Apr., Media Research: A Tool for Effective Advertising (Box 64)
        - 1956 Spring, Magazines Since the Rise of Television (Box 64)
        - 1956, Patterns of Change in the Post-War Era (Box 64)
        - 1957 Jan.-Mar., Magazines Adopting 'New Look' to Keep Pace with TV (Box 64)
        - 1957 July, review of The Hidden Persuaders by Vance Packard (Box 64)
        - 1957, Opinion Research and Marketing (Box 64)
        - 1957-1958 Winter, Measuring the Effectiveness of an Overseas Information Campaign: A Case History (Box 64)
        - 1958 Apr., review of Motivation Research and Marketing Management by Joseph W. Newman (Box 64)
        - 1958, review of Television Advertising by Clark M. Agnew and Neil O'Brien (Box 64)
        - 1959 Summer, Changing Markets and Media in Latin America (Box 64)
        - 1959, review of Introduction to Mass Communications Research edited by Ralph O. Nafziger and David Manning White (Box 64)
        - 1960 Jan., review of TV Advertising by Arthur Bellaire (Box 64)
        - 1960 Dec., review of The Strategy of Desire by Ernest Dichter (Box 64)
        - 1961 Jan., A New Look at the Beer Market (Box 64)
        - 1962 Jan., How Do People Read Newspapers? (Box 64)
        - 1962 Jan., The Researcher's Dilemma (Box 64)
        - 1962, American Television: A Brief Survey of Research Findings (Box 64)
        - 1963 Jan., Careers in Communications Research (Box 65)
        - 1963 Jan., review of Living with Television by Ira O. Glick and Sidney J. Levy (Box 65)
        - 1963 Winter, Inside Marketing Research (Box 65)
        - 1963 Winter, Newspapers in the Age of TV (Box 65)
        - 1964 Feb., review of The Advertising Rate Structure in the Daily Newspaper Industry by James M. Ferguson (Box 65)
        - 1964 June, The Impact of Blank Space: An Experiment in Advertising Readership by Leo Bogart and B. Stuart Tolley (Box 65)
        - 1964 Sept., What Happens When Ads are Blanked Out? (Box 65)
        - 1964, review of The Advertising Man in London Advertising Agencies by Jeremy Tunstall (Box 65)
        - 1965 Spring, Mass Media and Community Identity in an Interurban Setting by Leo Bogart and Frank E. Orenstein (Box 65)
        - 1965 Sept., Take a Closer Look at Product Users (Box 65)
        - 1965 Fall, review of Documentary in American Television by William A. Bluem (Box 65)
        - 1965, Pojam Publike U Americkim Istraživanjima Komunikacija (Box 65)
        - 1965, Three Explosions: Mass Media, Mass Advertising, Mass Marketing (Box 65)
        - 1966 Jan., Is it Time to Discard the Audience Concept? (Box 65)
        - 1966 Spring, Is There a World Public Opinion? (Box 65)
        - 1966 Oct., The Trend to Print in Advertising (Box 65)
        - 1967 Spring, review of Studies in Broadcasting: An International Annual of Broadcasting Science edited by Katagiri, Akinori, and Shinnosuke (Box 65)
        - 1967 June, The Today Factor in Media (Box 65)
        - 1967 July, How Mass Media Make Markets (Box 65)
        - 1967 Sept.-Oct., review of Mass Communication and Advertising by Karl-Erik Werneryd and Kjell Nowak (Box 65)
        - 1967 Fall, No Opinion, Don't Know, and Maybe No Answer (Box 65)
        - 1967, review of Consumer Choice in the American Economy by Carolyn Shaw Bell (Box 65)
        - 1967, Mass Media in the Year 2000 (Box 65)
        - 1968 Aug., Cost Per Thousand What? (Box 65)
        - 1968 Summer, The Overseas Newsman: A 1967 Profile Study (Box 66)
        - 1968 Sept., The Newspaper of the Future II - Outlook for Advertising (Box 66)
        - 1968 Oct., The Marketer as a Radical (Box 66)
        - 1968 Nov., Black is Often White: Negroes and the Mass Media (Box 66)
        - 1968, review of Integration of the Negro in the Armed Forces by Richard J. Stillman II (Box 66)
        - 1968-1969 Winter, Changing News Interests and the News Media (Box 66)
        - 1969 Mar., Where Does Advertising Research Go From Here? (Box 66)
        - 1969 June, review of The New Mass Media: Challenge to a Free Society by Gilbert Seldes (Box 66)
        - 1969 Summer, Violence in the Mass Media (Box 66)
        - 1969 Nov., How the Mass Media Work in America, in Mass Media and Violence, a report to the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence (Box 66)
        - 1969, Le Contrôle des Mass Media (Box 66)
        - 1969, review of Urban America, Inc. and the Urban Coalition, One Year Later (Box 66)
        - 1970 Aug., What One Little Ad Can Do by Leo Bogart, B. Stuart Tolley, and Frank Orenstein (Box 66)
        - 1970, A Newspaper Researcher Sees Television Changing (Box 66)
        - 1971 Jan., How CATV Will Affect Newspapers and Retailers (Box 66)
        - 1971 Apr., Youth Market isn't All That Different (Box 66)
        - 1971 Sept., Reaching People Where They Buy (Box 66)
        - 1971 Nov., Relating Media Strategy to Sales (Box 66)
        - 1971, review of Aspirations and Affluence: Comparative Studies in the United States and Western Europe by Katona, Strumpel, and Zahn (Box 66)
        - 1972 May, Customers, Not 'Consumers' (Box 66)
        - 1972 Spring, Negro and White Media Exposure: New Evidence (Box 66)
        - 1972, U.S. Newspapers: Status and Outlook (Box 66)
        - 1972, Warning: The Surgeon General Has Determined that TV Violence is Moderately Dangerous to Your Child's Mental Health, 4 folders (Box 67)
        - 1973 Feb., The Future of Retailing, 2 folders (Box 67)
        - 1973 Feb., What Makes a Brand Name Familiar? by Leo Bogart and Charles Lehman (Box 67)
        - 1973 May, Comment on Silk and Geiger (Box 67)
        - 1973 Oct., As Media Change, How Will Advertising? (Box 67)
        - 1973 Nov., Psychology on a Large Scale: The Study of Consumption (Box 67)
        - 1973, review of Journalists at Work. Specialist Correspondents: Their News Organizations, News Sources, and Competitor-Colleagues by Jeremy Tunstall (Box 67)
        - 1973, The Management of Mass Media: An Agent for Research (Box 67)
        - 1973, The Mass Media in America (Box 67)
        - 1973, What is Consumerism? (Box 67)
        - 1974 Sept.-Oct., Urban Papers Under Pressure (Box 67)
        - 1975 Spring, Media Models: A Reassessment (Box 67)
        - 1975 Spring, The Future of the Metropolitan Daily (Box 67)
        - 1975 Nov., The Marketing of Public Goods (Box 67)
        - 1975 Fall, How the Challenge of Television News Affects the Prosperity of Daily Newspapers (Box 67)
        - 1976 July-Aug., A Smart, Mobile, Cosmopolitan Generation (Box 67)
        - 1976 Sept.-Oct., Mass Advertising: The Message, Not the Measure, 4 folders (Box 68)
        - 1977 Jan., comment on Walter J. Primeaux, Jr., The Newspaper Rate Differential: Another Element in the Explanation (Box 68)
        - 1977 Aug., The Automobile as Social Cohesion (Box 68)
        - 1978 June, Talking with Towers About What's New in Newspapers (Box 68)
        - 1978 Oct., Is All This Advertising Necessary? (Box 68)
        - 1979 Feb., Does TV News Substitute for Newspapers? (Box 68)
        - 1979 Spring, Editorial Ideals, Editorial Illusions (Box 68)
        - 1980 Jan., The '80s: Readership (Box 68)
        - 1980 Apr., Newspapers Fight Off Broadcast Challenge, Survive and Prosper (Box 68)
        - 1980 Nov., Print vs. Broadcast: The NAB's Rebuttal (Box 68)
        - 1981, review of The Public's Use of Television: Who Watches and Why by Ronald E. Frank and Marshall G. Greenberg (Box 68)
        - 1982 Mar., The Marketing Environment for Technological Change (Box 68)
        - 1982 Mar., Media and a Changing Environment (Box 68)
        - 1982 Summer, comments on Public Attitudes Toward Freedom of the Press (Box 68)
        - 1982 Oct., Measuring the Effects of Advertising Research (Box 68)
        - 1982, Newspapers in Transition (Box 69)
        - 1982, review of The Politics of Crisis Reporting: Learning to be a Foreign Correspondent by John Crothers Pollock (Box 69)
        - 1982, Will Newspapers Become a Class Medium? Why They Need Not and Must Not (Box 69)
        - 1983 Jan., Smoking, Advertising, and Psychology (Box 69)
        - 1983 Mar., review of Mass Media and Social Change edited by Elihu Katz and Tamas Szecsko (Box 69)
        - 1983 Apr., The Fight for Readers: Declaring a Victory in a War that Will Never End (Box 69)
        - 1983 June, Prospects for Advertising (Box 69)
        - 1983 Aug., Making Use of Burgoon (Box 69)
        - 1983 Oct., The Great Reader Interest in International News (Box 69)
        - 1983 Winter, review of Books: The Culture and Commerce of Publishing by Lewis A. Coser, Charles Kadushin, and Walter A. Powell (Box 69)
        - 1983, The Case of the 30-Second Commercial by Leo Bogart and Charles Lehman (Box 69)
        - 1983, Public Opinion and Collective Behavior (Box 69)
        - 1983, review of The Rise and Fall of the Political Press in Britain by Stephen Koss (Box 69)
        - 1983-1984 Dec.-Jan., It's Important for Newspapers to 'Touch the Reader's Heart' (Box 69)
        - 1984 May, Hitting the Right Consumer Target (Box 69)
        - 1984 Winter, The Public's Use and Perception of Newspapers (Box 69)
        - 1984, Black and White Attitudes Toward the Newspaper (Box 69)
        - 1984, Newspapers in 2084 (Box 69)
        - 1984, review of The Rise and Fall of the Political Press in Britain: vol. 2 by Stephen Koss (Box 69)
        - 1985 Jan., Readership (Box 69)
        - 1985 Jan., War of the Words: Advertising in the Year 2010 (Box 69)
        - 1985 Mar., Both News and Advertising Expand as the Newspapers Get Fatter (Box 69)
        - 1985 Spring, How Newspaper Content is Changing (Box 69)
        - 1985 Sept., review of Technologies of Freedom: On Free Speech in an Electronic Age by Ithiel de Sola Pool (Box 69)
        - 1985 Nov.-Dec., Polls and Public Opinion (Box 69)
        - 1985 Winter, review of La Prensa Gratuita by Alfonso Nieto (Box 69)
        - 1985, review of The Politics of TV Violence: Policy Uses of Communication Research by Willard D. Rowland, Jr. (Box 70)
        - circa 1985, Tidningar År 2085 (Newspapers Year 2085) (Box 70)
        - 1986 Feb.-Mar., What Forces Shape the Future of Advertising Research? (Box 70)
        - 1986 Mar., La Publicité a l'Horizon 2010 (Box 70)
        - 1986 June-July, Progress in Advertising Research? (Box 70)
        - 1986 Summer, review of The American Journalist: A Portrait of U.S. News People and Their Work by David H. Weaver and G. Cleveland Wilhoit (Box 70)
        - 1987 June, What the Scanners Show (Box 70)
        - 1987, review of Distinction: A Social Critique of the Judgment of Taste by Pierre Bourdieu (Box 70)
        - 1987, The Future Study of Public Opinion, edited by Leo Bogart, 3 folders (Box 70)
        - 1988 Apr.-May, The Search for Information in Newspaper Advertising (Box 70)
        - 1988 May-June, The Multiple Meanings of Television Advertising (Box 70)
        - 1988 Summer, Research as an Instrument of Power (Box 70)
        - 1988 Oct., Advertisers Want Lower Rates (Box 70)
        - 1988-1989 Dec.-Jan., Advertising: Art, Science, or Business? (Box 70)
        - 1989 May, Can Newspaper Competition be Revived? (Box 70)
        - 1989 Sept., Classified: Buy It, Sell It, Find It (Box 70)
        - 1989 Fall, review of Reporting of Social Science in the National Media by Carol H. Weiss and Eleanor Singer (Box 70)
        - 1989, Mass Communication and World Opinion (Box 70)
        - 1989-2005, Presstime columns
          - Column ideas (Box 70)
          - Correspondence (Box 70)
          - Printed articles (Box 71)
          - Typed articles and drafts, 3 folders (Box 71)
        - 1990 Feb.-Mar., Advertising in 2020: How Perfect a Vision? (Box 71)
        - 1990 Winter, The Culture Beat: A Look at the Numbers (Box 71)
        - 1991 Mar., The American Media System and Its Commercial Culture (Box 71)
        - 1991 Sept.-Oct., American Media and Commercial Culture (Box 71)
        - 1991 Nov.-Dec., review of The Opinion Connection: Polling, Politics, and the Press by Albert H. Cantril (Box 71)
        - 1992 June, Farewell to the Bureau (Box 71)
        - 1992 July-Aug., Those Invisible Polls (Box 71)
        - 1992 Sept., The Future of Newspaper Revenues (Box 71)
        - 1992, review of The Super Pollsters by David W. Moore (Box 71)
        - 1993 Mar., Freedom to Know or Freedom to Say? (Box 71)
        - 1993 Apr., Aiming the Newspaper at the Customer (Box 71)
        - 1993 Spring, Newspapers of the Future: Our Look at the Next Century (Box 71)
        - 1993 July, Shaping a New Media Policy (Box 71)
        - 1993 July-Aug., Media Habits of Media Tycoons (Box 71)
        - 1993, Die Meinungsforscherin und die Nazis (The Pollster and the Nazis), 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 71)
        - 1993, Die Meinungsforscherin und die Nazis (The Pollster and the Nazis) (continued), 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 72)
        - 1993, Los Periódicos del Futuro (Box 72)
        - 1994 Mar.-Apr., Who Pays for the Media? (Box 72)